<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://vraneskoy.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://vraneskoy.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2025-08-11T03:37:40+00:00</updated><id>https://vraneskoy.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>A simple, whitespace theme for academics. Based on [*folio](https://github.com/bogoli/-folio) design. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Young Mathematicians Conference</title><link href="https://vraneskoy.github.io/blog/2025/YMC/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Young Mathematicians Conference"/><published>2025-08-05T15:12:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-08-05T15:12:00+00:00</updated><id>https://vraneskoy.github.io/blog/2025/YMC</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://vraneskoy.github.io/blog/2025/YMC/"><![CDATA[<p> I had the best time presenting at the Young Mathematicians Conference in Ohio last week! It was so exciting to see what other REUs have been working on this summer. Even though some of the talks went over my head, I really enjoyed meeting other undergrads and talking with faculty. </p> <p> One of my favorite talks was by Ryan Hynd (UPenn), who spoke about dynamic games involving large numbers of interacting agents, using tools from game theory, probability, and partial differential equations. I was definitely lost at times, but I found the ideas fascinating. It definetly inspired me to look over my copy of Evans again afrewards haha. </p> <p> I also attended a fantastic talk by Cary Malkiewich (Binghamton University) on the scissors congruence problem. I hadn’t encountered anything like it before, so it was especially interesting. It was my first time seeing the kind of proofs mathematicians use for problems like this, and I learned a lot. </p> <p> Overall, the conference was a great experience. It gave me a chance to explore different fields, hear about the grad school application process, and learn how various faculty members found their way into their areas of research. What stood out to me was how many of them arrived at their fields by coincidence rather than having everything figured out as undergrads. Honestly, that was reassuring to hear. While my experience at SMALL made me realize that I'm especially drawn to Analysis and PDEs side of things, I think it is nice to be able to look around and see what else is happening in the math community. Looking forward to what comes next! </p> <p> Special thanks to the YMC organizers, OSU faculty, Cookie Monster and all the people who came to our talk! </p> <div class="row mt-3"> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/YMC_group-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/YMC_group-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/YMC_group-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/YMC_group.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/YMC_presenting-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/YMC_presenting-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/YMC_presenting-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/YMC_presenting.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> <div class="col-sm mt-3 mt-md-0"> <figure> <picture> <source class="responsive-img-srcset" srcset="/assets/img/YMC_cookiemonster-480.webp 480w,/assets/img/YMC_cookiemonster-800.webp 800w,/assets/img/YMC_cookiemonster-1400.webp 1400w," type="image/webp" sizes="95vw"/> <img src="/assets/img/YMC_cookiemonster.jpg" class="img-fluid rounded z-depth-1" width="100%" height="auto" data-zoomable="" loading="eager" onerror="this.onerror=null; $('.responsive-img-srcset').remove();"/> </picture> </figure> </div> </div> <div class="caption"> Some pictures from the conference! </div>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="undergraduate-posts"/><category term="talks"/><category term="conferences"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[new friends in ohio and other places]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">my worst talk (and my best talk)</title><link href="https://vraneskoy.github.io/blog/2025/math/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="my worst talk (and my best talk)"/><published>2025-07-26T15:12:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-07-26T15:12:00+00:00</updated><id>https://vraneskoy.github.io/blog/2025/math</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://vraneskoy.github.io/blog/2025/math/"><![CDATA[<p> This past Wednesday, I had the chance to present on the Signal Recovery project I’ve been working on under the supervision of Prof. Eyvindur Palsson and Prof. Alex Iosovich. Before presenting, I felt fairly confident in my abilities, but as the time approached, my nerves started tingling with excitement and fear. I’d never given a talk before, so right before we went in, Prof. Miller told me: "Today, you are going to deliver your worst talk ... and the best one at the same time". It was a pretty accurate observation. The talk went pretty smoothly, give or take a stumble or two. And my planted joke actually got five whole laughs, so I’m counting that as a success. <p> <p> My main goal was to maintain the balance during my talk. We didn’t have time to go through all the behind-the-scenes math that my team and I tackled to get the results, and we also couldn’t assume much background knowledge since most of the audience wasn’t in our field. At the same time, we didn’t want people mentally checking out halfway through because things got too dense or too dry. My teammates and I tried to thread the needle - fill in enough context to make the work understandable, but still keep it lively and (hopefully) memorable. And, if I may say so myself, I think we pulled it off. <p> <p> Next week, I’ll be presenting similar material at the Young Mathematician Conference in Ohio, and I’m genuinely so excited. We’ll be seeing some friends we made at Yale this week and meeting a bunch more.<p> <p> Huge thanks to Say-Yeon and Meiling for preping the talk with me, to Prof. Steven Miller for pulling the whole conference together and buying us ice cream on the way back, and to Steve for driving us all the way to Yale from Williamstown :)<p> </p></p></p></p></p></p></p></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="undergraduate-posts"/><category term="talks"/><category term="conferences"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[exciting developments]]></summary></entry></feed>